Guide to the Fales Library Events Video Collection 1990-2016 MSS 307
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library Events Video Collection
1990-2016
MSS 307
Fales Library and Special Collections
6.0 linear feet
Historical Note
The Fales Library Events Video Collection contains video and audio of events either arranged by or held at the Fales Library relating to the Fales Library, Fales archival collections and/or the Fales Food Studies Series.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into three series:
Fales Events Videos
Fales Food Studies Events
Submasters (Restricted Access)
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Scope and Content
This collection contains video and audio of events either arranged by or held at Fales Library.
- Series I: Fales Events Videos
  - ACT UP; Read My Lips; Fales Library, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Format: VHS
  - Artist's Circles: What They Do, How Do They Work, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0002)
    Format: DVD
  - Campus Flash: Fales Library and Special Collections, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0003)
  - The Downtown Show; Creating the Archive, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0004)
  - The Downtown Show; The Moving Edge, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0005)
  - The Downtown Show; No Alternative, New Downtown Art, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0006)
  - The Downtown Show; Readings From the Downtown Book, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0007)
  - The Downtown Show; Scholars and Artists 2, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0008)
  - The Downtown Show; Simon Reynolds, Rip It Up Start Again, Post-Punk 78-84, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0009)
  - Great Books: Alice in Wonderland, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0010)
  - Great Books: All Quiet On The Western Front, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0011)
  - Six Years After the NEA 4: Karen Finley, John Fleck, Holly Hughes, Tim Miller, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0013)
  - Television is 70 with Dr. Malcolm H.I. Baird, Undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0014)
  - The Making of Alice in Wonderland: Narrated by Lorrie Goulet [Jud 'Alba], 1994 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0015)
  - Edward Robb Ellis; NYU, November 13, 1996 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0016)
  - Fales Archive: The Downtown Project; Sharon Mesmer, Max Blagg, October 27, 1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0017)
  - Dr. John Chambers in Fales, November 11, 1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0018)
  - City Arts [512]: David Wojnarowicz. Duke Ellington. Famous Where I Came From, January 29, 1999 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0019)
  - David Wojnarowicz in Fales [Part 1], February 4, 1999 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0020)
  - David Wojnarowicz in Fales [Part 2], February 4, 1999 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0021)
  - Beautiful: The Writing of Dennis Cooper, March 2, 2000 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0022)
  - Beautiful: The Writing of Dennis Cooper, March 3, 2000 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0023)
  - The Tattoed Man Tells All, May 15, 2000 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0024)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 1, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0025)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 2, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0026)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 3, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0027)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 4, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0028)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 5, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0029)
  - Fales Library Reading: Anti-War Poetry Reading, February 12, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0030)
  - Visions for a Changing Theatre: Panel 1-Seeking Paradise, Ocotober 9, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0031)
  - Visions for a Changing Theatre: Panel 2-Eyeing Parnassus, Ocotober 9, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0032)
  - Visions for a Changing Theatre: Panel 3-Decoding Utopia, Ocotober 9, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0033)
  - Visions for a Changing Theatre: Panel 4-Making Waves, Ocotober 9, 2003 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0086)
  - Fales Event Up is Up But So Is Down; Downtown Lit, October 26, 2006 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0037)
  - Dennis Cooper: Enter at One's Own Risk, Transgressive Writing, March 1, 2007 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0040)
  - The Fales Collection at the Elmer Holmes Bobst Library; Writing New York: Tales from Gotham City, April 17, 2007 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0042)
  - Orphan 6: SAMMA Demonstration - Clips, March 29, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0046)
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - Video Clips, April 3, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0048)
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - "Signal Loss: Saving Downtown Video", April 4, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0049)
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - "Not Your Home Movies: Downtown Film", April 4, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0050)
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - "Not Your Home Movies: Downtown Film", April 4, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0051)
    Format: Audiocassette
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - "Not Your Home Movies: Downtown Film", April 4, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0052)
  - Fales Series - How A.I.R. Changed the World, September 16, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0054)
  - A.I.R. Gallery The History Show, November 18, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0056)
  - 2009 Fales Lecture in English and American Literature: "Is There a Future for the Literary Novel?, April 14, 2009 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0062)
  - The Unbearables - Readings from The Worst Book I Ever Read, September 27, 2009 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0065)
  - The Children of Burroughs - New York Arts and Legacy of Naked Lunch, October 8, 2009 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0066)
  - You Are Cordially Invited: The Art and Influence of Robert Blanchon, January 2, 2010 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0070)
  - Fales: New Media, March 25, 2010 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0071)
  - Where is Ana Mendieta? (at Tisch School of the Arts), October 7, 2010 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0073)
  - At Moments Like These He Feels Furthest Away, January 26, 2011 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0075)
  - Mary Ellen Solt: Toward a Theory of Concrete Poetry, October 27, 2010 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0076)
  - Visual AIDS: "What Comes Next?", April 20, 2011 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0078)
  - Fluxus Conversation: Ben Kinmont and Julia Robinson, September 16, 2011 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0079)
  - Fluxus Amongst Us: Insight and Transformation in Fluxus Encounters, Part I, October 18, 2011 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0080)
  - Fluxus Amongst Us: Insight and Transformation in Fluxus Encounters, Part II, October 18, 2011 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0081)
  - Paper Tiger, February 3, 2012 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0082)
    File Plan note
  - Henry Abelove Symposium, February 16, 2012 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0083)
    Related Archival Materials note
  - Dievs Lecture, April 12, 2012 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0084)
  - Frank Moore: Together in Art and Activism, September 24, 2012 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0085)
  - Nelson Sullivan: Vlogging in the 80s, April 25, 2013 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0091)
  - Catherine Opie, September 12, 2013 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0093)
  - Sterling Lord, October 24, 2013 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0094)
  - Whither Collectiong? New Visions for Special Collections in the 21st Century, November 20, 2013 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0095)
  - Duncan & Jess: Between Fields, March 6, 14 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0097)
  - GoNightclubbing, March 20, 2014 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0099)
  - Books as Social Media, April 2, 2014 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0100)
  - Dismantling Invisibility, May 4, 2015; 3.0 media elements (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0103)
    Format: Playable DVD and Data DVD
  - Celebration of Linda Montano, April 14, 2015; 3.0 media elements (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0104)
  - Charles Walters: The Director Who Made Hollywood Dance, February 12, 2015; 3.0 media elements (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0105)
  - Off-Off Broadway's Origins at Caff Cino, March 11, 2015; 3.0 media elements (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0107)
  - Fales Lecture in English & American Literature: Histories of the Alphabet, April 1, 2015 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0109)
- Series II: Fales Food Studies Events
  - Critical Topics; Food Series Pt. 1; Fales Library, May 17, 2005 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0034)
  - Fales Food Series: Women Who Cook for a Living, June 14, 2006 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0035)
  - Food Series: The Chains and Systems of Food, October 19, 2006 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0036)
  - Fales Food Series: A Celebration of the Publication of the United States of Arugala David Kamp, October 26, 2006 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0038)
  - Fales Food Series: What's With All These Books on Food?, December 12, 2006 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0039)
  - Fales Food Series: Cooking with Color, March 8, 2007 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0041)
  - Fales Food Series: Building a Food Professional Pedigree: The New Roads to Knowledge and Success, June 14, 2007 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0043)
  - Fales Food Series: Cooks Who Grow Their Own: A More Direct Route From Earth to Table, October 11, 2007 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0044)
  - Fales Food Series: The Power of the Pen: The Role of Editors in Writings on Food, March 13, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0053)
  - Fales Food Series Emerging and Disappearing: Immigrant Foodways, October 16, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0055)
  - Fales Food Series: A Reading and Celebration of American Cheeses by Clark Wolf, December 3, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0057)
  - Fales Food Series: "The Enduring Impact and Influence of James Beard on American Food", May 1, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0058)
  - Fales Food Series: "Water: A Global Discussion of a Critical Topic", June 5, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0059)
  - Fales Food Series: "20 Years of Food Arts; 30 Years of Food and Wine: How Food and Food Writing Have Changed in America, November 20, 2008 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0060)
  - Fales Food Series: "Food and Celebration: A Long History of What Brings Us Together", March 5, 2009 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0061)
  - Fales Food Series: New York Farm Connections: The Five Boroughs as Farmland & Marketplace, June 4, 2009 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0063)
  - Fales Food Series: Food Show: When Performance Becomes Lunch, October 15, 2009 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0067)
  - Fales Food Series: Who's Who and What's What: The Evolution of the Food Cognoscenti in America, November 5, 2009 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0068)
  - Fales Food Series: Why (and exactly how) New York Simply Loves Italian, February 3, 2009 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0069)
  - Fales Food Series: Me In A Book With Recipes, 2010 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0072)
  - Fales Food Series: Back Into the Kitchen, November 4, 2010 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0074)
  - Fales Food Series: Harvesting the Roots of Today's Farming and Artisan Cookery Through Oral History, June 9, 2011 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA 0077)
  - Fales Food Series: Changing the American Plate: "The Meat of the Matter", October 20, 2011 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0087)
  - Fales Food Series: Yelp? Help!, March 14, 2012 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0088)
  - Fales Food Series: Fales Food Fight: A Closer Look at the 2012 Farm Bill, May 3, 2012 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0089)
  - Fales Food Series: The Cookbook Book: Why Books and Benchmarks Matter, October 25, 2012 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0090)
  - Fales Food Series: Food Politics, May 30, 2013 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0092)
  - Fales Food Series: Why Cookbooks Still Matter, December 4, 2013 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0096)
  - Fales Food Series: Looking Back to Go Forward Ancient Ways in Modern Food, March 13, 2014 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0098)
  - Fales Food Series: In Your Glass! The Evolution of Libtation at the American Table, June 5, 2014 (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0101)
  - Fales Food Series: What Exactly is Cooking?, June 4, 2015; 3.0 media elements (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0102)
  - Fales Food Series: Food in the 21st Century, October 9, 2014; 2.0 media elements (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0106)
  - Fales Food Series: What is Sustainability Exactly?, April 2, 2015; 3.0 media elements (Shelf Media, Media ID: FA0108)
- Series III: Submasters (Restricted Access)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Items in Series III: Submasters is restricted to researchers.
  - Submasters A, 1990-2016 (Box 1)
  - Submasters B, 1990-2016 (Box 2)